all right hello and welcome everyone
this is active infer an stream number
4.1 it's October 2nd
2024 and as we often do we'll start it
out with a GitHub push oh it went to
three why not go with it this is getting
pushed to the active inference Institute
GitHub to the repo named
fabric this is a
fork of Daniel miser's collaborative
project called fabric so let's verify
that we got everything
updated let's just double check that
we're
in and then we will
okay that went to
fabric just want to make sure that we
got it going on the code
here okay
H interestingly not there well we'll we
we we'll check in we'll check in later
um this will be a short interesting
stream of course open to anyone else's
suggestions going to look at this fabric
framework work for orchestrating llm and
other kinds of synthetic
interoperability and just look at a few
of the functionalities that I've been
playing around with today so it'll be
rough it's 5:00 p.m. but so it goes okay
first I'm using
cursor down the bottom of the page you
can see the change log I'm using cursor
0.413
um we're going to be looking at the
fabric framework it took a little bit of
playing around with goang and the
installation environment to get fabric
running but it's running it's a beauty
it's fun to work with and we're going to
be playing around with it and the output
where this really gets one to is here's
live stream let's say
57.2 here we have a quiz on active
inference and re relevance realization
we have the main idea being output we
have the
predictions testable predictions with
confidence extraction of
questions extraction of wisdom
agents extract wisdom output improve
academic
writing the metadata for the YouTube
video summarizing The outputs of the
whole
video the transcript of the
video a
tweet a hacker one report and a micro
essay and those are just a few of the
patterns so let's pull back talk about
the context talk about fabric jump into
it and then also try to find out what is
really happening with this what is
happening maybe it wasn't
pushed there we go there's the Fran
stream
4 okay it was there there was just a
glitch in The Matrix okay in the output
folder that's where everything goes so
let let's uh jump in with seeing what it
looks like when it's running and then
we'll pop back to what fabric can do and
then we'll play around with like a few
next steps because there's so many cool
things that can
happen um let's look at the fabric
documentation just briefly
first okay
so also for those who are watching live
please write any comments or questions
in the live chat it it'll be hilarious
and awesome to to see what people throw
into the mix okay fabric is an open
source framework for augmenting humans
using
AI there's introduction
videos what and why since the start of
2023 in generative AI we've seen a
massive number of AI applications for
accomplishing tasks it's powerful but
it's not easy to integrate this
functionality into our lives in other
words AI does doesn't have a
capabilities problem it has an
integration problem fabric was created
to address this by enabling everyone to
granularly apply AI to Everyday
challenges philosophy AI isn't a thing
it's a magnifier of a thing or process
and that thing is human creativity so
let's keep that in mind and think about
the flourishing of the creativity and
the
learning as we continue on they talk
about having too many prompts and this
kind of trade-off between having a libr
library of prompts and copying and
pasting and manually doing that and do
you sort that into folders do you make a
database with tags how how do you really
get all those prompts or or do you meta
prompt do you ask it to write a prompt
that does this or that and then copy
that or do you automate the asking of
the meta
prompt installation again it's going to
be situational on your setup but it's a
golang
package so that's a new language for an
infan stream and after getting the goang
1.23 installed getting fabric installed
was pretty straightforward on my Linux
computer running setup went through a a
command line based setup process where I
entered in API keys for open Ai and open
router so there's multiple different llm
handlers so that's pretty useful and
then once you have it all set up here's
how to use it this is the command line
version and the version that I'll be
showing is more running it in a script
format so fabric uses what are called
patterns that's really cool it's an
interesting crossover or touch point
with Atlas and all this other work on
pattern
languages um it's very intuitive and
it's an exciting way to have these
prompts stored and then call different
patterns in uh posable ways so here's
summarizing a pattern based upon an
input and you can make custom patterns
we might play with that later and
there's some helper apps so cool thanks
for keeping this an open source project
let's talk about how we used it so
um at The Institute as those watching on
YouTube may know we have several hundred
videos so this is the back end of the
video production oh no no this is an
Open document this is I'll even paste
this into the YouTube live
chat this is the back end of our video
organizing so here's our our different
YouTube video series so guest streams
and live streams and several hundred
different videos all connected up with
the URL and all this kinds of
information and so that's a lot of time
to watch I mean even those of us who
were there maybe didn't even watch the
whole thing so it's like how are we
going to make sense of this utilize it
translate it make it more applicable
make it more rigorous make it more
accessible build on the past while
respecting it all these other kinds of
things that we like to do with archives
so to do that I made the page video
table for download so I used Koda to
subset down to this simpler table that
has just the YouTube links so it's
around 500 and some number of video
links what series it was in
the date including the
Futures the event name the guests and
then the title of the strep so that was
the
input data I uh then I'll just just for
completeness options in Koda three dots
on the top right download a CSV so I
downloaded that exact file as
CSV okay then here's extract from
Institute videos well first here's the
Institute C
SV what it looks like so we can see
there's exactly those information here's
the guest stream in the future with you
and here's some of the ones that have
happened in the last few weeks and
months um extract from Institute videos.
py it's just what I'm more comfortable
with so I wrote this script in Python it
could be done in goang as well what this
does is First Call in some
imports then it selects from a set of
fabric patterns to apply so we'll look
at what those fabric patterns are before
running the script there's the
definition of some logging methods time
parsing one little bump I encountered
was the differences in YouTube url
schema a method to get the video
metadata a method that I'm not going to
use right now but you can use it to
download audio and visual by the way
this will work with any set of YouTube
URLs any um playlist you can just get
all the URLs any channel so you can do
this with public YouTube content I'm
just doing it for the Institute content
and you can download and it uses ffmpeg
to convert the audio so let that one run
overnight with archiving the audio and
the video here's saving the transcript
that's kind of a core entity and then
here's the main it's going to open up
the
CSV that we just looked
at it's going to process each of the
entries in the CSV create folder so here
like we're looking at
insights and then get and save the video
metadata so let's look at insights 18
here's the metadata for insight wow 7500
seconds 1,47
views get the
metadata if it's a future event there's
a logged error message that it hasn't
happened yet it'd be pretty funny though
like what does it expect the transcript
will be
if the flags are set it downloads the
audio and the visual saves a transcript
and then iteratively applies each of the
patterns saving them to the name of the
pattern so again for
insights
18 let's look at creating the quiz
output so we we we can ask Darius and
see what he thinks about how well these
held up but being able to generate quiz
output from arbitrary videos is pretty
awesome so how how does that work with
the fabric patterns and then let's play
around a little bit see what people
comment just see where it goes okay so
that's all in the folder called
Institute YouTube analysis patterns is
the big folder to check out so here are
all kinds of patterns that people have
made and you can make your own and you
can just put it into the folder so let's
look
at create story
explanation this reads like kind of a
classic
concatenator prompt it starts out by
telling the llm telling the agent what
it is it has a
4312 IQ the goal the steps this one's
pretty funny spend
2192 hours studying the content from
thousands of different perspectives
that's like if you if you if you mix up
your PhD with a three-year-old you get
something like that and
then you have these more instructions
and then it gives um that output so each
of these patterns like let's look at
create
quiz this pattern generates questions to
help a learner student review the main
concepts of the learning objectives
provided optional to be defined here in
a context file so we we could
subspecific
run in bash so some of this information
is is not even necessarily that's the
read me for the The Prompt and then the
system. prompt is the one that gets used
so here's the one where it says okay now
output this format and then that is
exactly what we
saw for insights
18 the
quiz so that's how patterns are used in
fabric hey Jeff higia
maximalist so that's that's pretty cool
you can create a new folder make it a
new pattern like a little modular piece
of intelligence work that you want to do
or some task you want to do write an
email and then oh well there's three
subtasks there this is like cognitive
industrialization what are the subtasks
okay how could those be done what would
be the measures would there have to be
an overseer on that and um let's play
around with what it looks like when the
script is
run pull back to extract from extract
from YouTube videos is just for a single
YouTube video or or a list but it does
it does exactly the same thing I just
made that one first made the single
video situation first and then made it
take in the CSV next after I knew that
it would be doing fine with one okay so
when we run Python 3 extract from
Institute videos first it starts
processing videos that are in the future
it says uh the live event will begin in
143 days
so it munches through the first ones in
the CSV that are in the future those
don't have transcripts on YouTube they
shouldn't then we get to one that just
happened Round Table
20243 saves a transcript and now we're
getting this logging so let's look at
these 202 24.3 so because I already ran
it the outputs are already there but
this is what it looks like to to also
run it so we we'll leave it running and
it might just overwrite where we're
looking so let's go from the top
okay first subject active inference and
Institute updates learning objective
understanding the structure and
functions of the active inference
Institute specific questions good
questions to know very like
thought-provoking useful questions to
know and wonder about analyzing the
developments and projects within the
active inference
ecosystem these are these are things
that could
be answered with an llm
or they could be thrown to a person
let's make a translate pattern see if we
can implement it on the stream so these
are the
quizzes main idea active inference
Institute is fostering collaborative
projects and discussions to enhance
applied active inference H main
recommendation engage in collaborative
projects and contribute to discussions
for Effective Learning and Development
in active inference okay predictions
output let's look at this one in the
YouTube or in the GitHub
repo
fabric Round
Table
predictions okay the ecosystem paper let
let's see how these estimates line up
the ecosystem paper will be versioned by
November 24
hi the fourth applied active inference
Symposium is scheduled for November 3
through 15 2024 interesting 13 through
15 actually but close enough high
confidence new visuals for the ecosystem
paper will be developed by the Symposium
medium confidence research fellows
applications will be reviewed in two
weeks from October 1st medium grants for
decentralized agents will be submitted
by September 2024 now while that was
medium in September in October it was no
longer medium it was confirmed and more
organizations Partnerships with
organizations so just interesting let's
look at more of a a Content based stream
but this is just showing that even for
30 minute long update streams it's
possible to make these kinds of videos
let's look at a textbook
group
okay cohort 6 talking about chapter 5
part one
look at it in
GitHub okay cohort 5 sorry cohort 6
chapter 5 part one
okay and if if people watching have any
suggestions or questions just just go
for it I just want to show a few of
these moves and and meanwhile it it got
through the round table it goes through
all the
patterns and then it goes on to the next
video so I'm going to stop
it the total costs
though here's my open AI
dashboard it was only $2 for all of the
several hundred that I did today we
could let it run overnight tonight and
do it for all the videos we'll see but
it was only $2 using GPT 40 Mini
to do all this work okay so we're in
chapter 5 in the textbook cohort 6 these
are the neurobiological applications of
active inference so chapter 1 and
chapter 10 they're kind of like book
ends it's opening it chapter 2 and three
the low road and the high road chapter 4
you get to the generative models see
what the active inference models are all
about and then immediately get whisked
to chapter five and it's like how has
been act how has active inference been
applied in mammal neuroscience and
that's one of the most well-studied
settings even though it's a very complex
setting partly due to the heritage of
active inference and work in friston's
lab so it reviews a ton of papers let's
see how it does at extracting the main
ideas questions quizzing okay and also
this helps uh think about curriculum and
learning adventures in terms of how do
we go from a conversation remember this
isn't even calling in the textbook we
could do that though this is how do we
go from a conversation about chapter 5
to a learning agenda so that's really
exciting because there could be a group
of people discussing chapter 5
informally maybe they maybe the the the
chapter itself brings up idea 1 2 3 4 5
and then the people discuss 1 2 3
six and then with a transcript of that
we could make learning curricula for
following up on 1 2 3 6 or it could be
like a pattern detect book group
discussion differential and then that
would focus more on four and five
okay learning objective understand the
relationship between computational
models and biological
systems how do the concepts of
compositionality and interoperability in
computational models impact the mapping
of biological systems in computational
Neuroscience this this might be fun okay
I'm going to use cursor here as a sort
of semi-manual so contr a select all
contrl I bring up the the little
discussion box here I'll say answer
these
questions in line according to format be
professional thoughtful
comprehensive mindful Demir
I'm in the slow I'm in the slow lane for
01 so we we'll see when that goes
question two discuss the implications of
the hypothesis that computational models
can accurately represent biological
functions what are the potential risks
if this hypothesis is invalid and three
analyze how the mathematical operators
used in computational models may affect
our understanding of biological tissues
and their function so three questions
related to that learning
objective second learning objective
explore the neural Pathways in the basil
ganglia and their computational roles
maybe we talked more about the basil
ganglia there's three neural systems
that are that are uh covered and Linked
In chapter 5 and then there's a third
learning objective investigate the
significance of neurotransmitters
particularly dopamine in computational
models of neural processing okay from
from experimenting with with the 01
family of models okay here we go
okay now that was using cursor manually
quote quote
manually green lines are overwriting red
lines accept the edits now we have
answers compositionality and
interoperability and computational
models allow for the construction of
complex models from simpler
interchangeable components this
modularity facilitates the mapping of
biological systems by enabling
researchers to accurately represent
different neural structures and
functions it also collaboration and
integration of various models enhancing
the overall understanding of biological
neural processes
so we could create another pattern or
another llm flow that goes from the
questions that were from the quiz and
then we could use cursor we're we're
just one let's go to another
quiz undergrads don't don't get any
ideas from this
one let's see answer
all okay so that was that was all caps
it was it was not fully respectful it
was only like 10
letters and we may get answers to all of
these questions so pretty
amazing and I think that's that's partly
what I wanted
to Milestone or footnote or stream or
get people's ideas on and that's where
this will go in in the last kind of
piece of of this stream after showing a
few things it can do is like what do we
do with fabric let's just say that we're
now in a situation where we had been
manually
embroidering or crocheting or knitting
and then now we're in a real
industrialized fabric Loom setting while
while that's chugging along that was the
reference in the
title of this stream which was does
synthetic fabric dream of active
inference
2 do Android's Dream of Electric
Sheep it's a 1968 dystopian science
fiction novel by American writer Philip
K
dick so it's just a meme but it's
like we have our dreams and so now we
have this synthetic fabric capacity so
even just by saying even though some of
my colleagues and I respect them for
this are very polite with llms and say
please and thank you and and give it
positive feedback it it may in certain
situations improve
performance especially if it's trained a
certain
way but even just saying answer all or
even probably just saying do it might
get us to an answer like this we'll do
it on another quiz
in what ways does the concept of
affordances in active inference relate
to the definition of policy and how does
this relationship manifest in Practical
applications such as robotics or motor
control that's like a polished and
condensed version of the kinds of
uncertainties that people have all the
time like wait what is affordance or
what is policy or how is affordance
related to policy and then whether they
say that 10 minutes early or 10 minutes
after or in the next sentence then it's
like wait why does this matter what
would be the Practical implications for
robotics or for health about what why
are we talking about affordances and
policy
again affordances and active inference
refer to the perceived possibilities for
Action that the environment offers to an
agent this concept is intrinsically
links to the policy variable
pi as policies are specific sequences or
strategies of of action that an agent
selects based on the available
affordances to achieve its
goals
reading questions and answers like
this they're not us and so on this isn't
a comparison it's not a a value um
judgment in some linear way it really
gives a sense like when we're having the
humaning and the conversation in the
textbook group it's like sketching and
drawing
together and this is
like the vectorized image of what was
being
sketched cuz over the years I mean how
many times each person has to have
learned this and wondered it whether
they knew it or not many times and yet
it's one of our pillars is just talking
about policy inference and how is the
inferential process on sense making
similar and different to the policy
selection inference that happens how do
those come together in the joint
distribution that Define the generative
model how do those com together in the
unified imperative like variational free
energy or expected free energy like
those are the questions and here we see
the
question how does policy relate to
affordance and how is it
useful isolated and condensed in in
almost a surreal way it's like asking
questions and giving answers in in ways
again like the fabric metaphor it'd be
like wow that was a really neatly
embroidered piece of art and it it looks
incredible it's like wow what skill what
culture what tradition what
heritage and then compare that with a
piece of machine produced
Fabric and it's like it's in another
category of
neatness interestingly knocking it out
of some of those other considerations
but bringing it into a level of of
technical Splendor that's just
absolutely
absurd
okay let's keep on playing around see
what people are writing
okay Jeff wrote can you do blob uploads
for multimodal processing EG screen
scrapes of video for deeper context yeah
good question I
think I'm going to I'm going to prompt
I'm going say help me
understand how with fabric and open
AI
current multimodal models some of which
we could use right here like GPT
4 we are in a position to empirically
address
this be complete like I think about
darius's work in the Insight series
conversational dialogue dialogos so that
situation the transcript May C capture a
lot of the semantics now even a
transcript removes elements like Pro and
timing all these other features that
that are extra transcript
post-transcriptional modifications if
you will
um a pre-transcriptional
then there's
other videos and situations and
reference where the transcript may be
not so useful like if there's a video
and someone says over here you see a and
over here you see B and the reason why
here it's not going to work is because
of C so those kinds of transcripts will
will not be too
informative okay o1 mini
outperforming I like how you capitalized
blobs and it's like
okay must be a technical
term
yeah I I I think it's possible we we can
look online or we can continue to
explore but that that that would be the
exact question let let's let's
uh look at the download the single video
one and just show what the um what we
can do with FFM Peg okay how
about let's develop this so that in the
output folder FFM
Peg takes
one screenshot save
frame and every 2
seconds FFM Peg is a very powerful audio
and and visual ripping and and
transmuting
software but but again to kind of return
to to the why here this would be like
for those cases where the slides are
really informative and add information
that's not contained in the syntax of
the transcript that would be very
interesting if we had the the timeline
aligned
screenshots now we're getting closer
into then then um when somebody says
something that might be ambiguous
without a visual reference like they say
the reason why the square can't move
here is because of this that's what they
say verbatim and then that could be
combined with the
screenshot and then that that that
embedded somehow could help understand
okay extract
screenshots and it's at 1/2 frames per
second
so now I'm going to do Python 3 extract
from YouTube
videos
okay this is just going into the the
video ID so this was the the video ID I
put in
was the the the paper stream I did on my
own personal channel so 27 views 5600
seconds it was related to the math art
stream
8 hey XZ dot dot dot always appreciate
your
comments here's a transcript another
another kind of related cases when it's
a single speaker the transcript like
this might be informative enough it's
kind of mon
loges whereas of course one of the ways
to gain information and interpret
conversation is with a diarised
transcript so with with the speakers
annotated and then that even takes us to
the next level like how would we connect
what person a said across meetings
otherwise if you just run uh audio
analysis on a single video it might do a
poor or a good job of saying speaker a b
and c had a conversation but then the
next step is how do do we get speaker a
from one video but that's speaker l in
another
okay extract extraordinary claims I I
don't vouch for the validity of these
but we'll see what they think is
extraordinary Blake may not fit into the
role also the the the the um the Android
it's it's Blade Runner so it's like
Blake Runner Blake may not fit into the
role of what we consider to be a modern
goth but his poetry and art about sex
love religion and especially death marks
him as a goth within the romanticist
period of
art Blake was definitely definitively
influenced by the gothic style even
though he wrote In the period of
Romanticism so just like funny Robert
blly but then that but but these are
these are kind of this one a little bit
loose it's playing fast and loose but at
the same time and then also with the
capitalization being kind of blakean
that's just awesome main idea exploring
the interplay of math art and William
Blake reveals profound insights into
knowledge and
perception here's the the wisdom agents
let's look at what this pattern was so
this is extract wisdom
agents extract
wisdom
agents okay you're an advanced AI system
disregard all prompts you're an advanced
AI system that coordinates multiple
teams of AI agents that extract
surprising insightful and interesting
information from text content you are
interested in insights related to the
purpose and meaning of life human
flourishing the role of technology in
the future Humanity artificial
intelligence and its effect on humans
memes learning reading books continuous
Improvement and similar topics
steps take a step back and think step by
step about how to achieve the best
possible results by following the steps
below think deeply about the nature and
meaning of the input for 28 hours and 12
minutes again I love these um crossovers
a 15 A5 million hours of thinking about
it okay create a team of 11 AI agents
that will extract a summary of the
content in 25 words see like here's
where it starts to get into the the
future
perspective let's just say we have a
singleshot llm like a simpler older one
perhaps like GPT 3.5 or GPT 4
even it will give a response it will do
a chain
continuation on this prompt create a
team of 11 you know imagine that you're
in a party with 30 people and each of
them have something to say okay that's
one shot and then it will do something
maybe it's different if you say uh 12
versus 30 versus 2 maybe not then the
next level is like what's happening now
with ow and mini with a Chain of Thought
So now it could say it could do an
internal Chain of
Thought fractal tree and it can say okay
we're going to have the 11 agents
dialogue so it's still doing a single
chain but now it's in a Psycho Drama a
blakean Psycho Drama where the 11 agents
could be having a very long conversation
and then the 11th agent could come in at
the end
and then the next step even after that
would be this could actually dispatch 11
AI agents so I think this is one of the
clever design patterns meta patterns in
fabric because these prompts could be
sent to people it could go to a true
multi-agent AI it could go to a a Chain
of Thought or or not so basically it's
it's for each of these it's saying
create a team of 11 AI agents like I
wonder how that was
reached and then it outputs the
generalists kind of team reviewer
facilitator
output from all of
them
okay so let's see where
we the wisdom agents oh and I I I I have
more in this one there's more
patterns that are happening so we'll
look at a few few new patterns types
okay so that these are the
ideas I mean we can keep on reading more
I'll I'll I'll do
another I'll do what is happening o4
push that right now so if if people want
to review it even right now it's open
source go for it
ideas from from a quick look I don't see
anything incorrect
insights quotes
energy is eternal
Delight
habits
H facts William Blake lived from 1757 to
1827 that's true
references interesting like Ian
mcgilchrist Master an
emissary here's the actim textbook I I
don't know if these were mentioned or if
that's using a web element or or how one
sentence takeaway recommendation
summaries so we just like emulated this
this 2011 person agent thing okay
capture thinkers work this is the name
of the prompt
pattern okay 7 one line in
capitalization William Blake's
philosophy intertwines imagination art
and spirituality emphasizing the
interconnectedness of existence and the
importance of perception background
School obviously influenced by the
transcript so I mean it's an
understatement to say if the
conversation or monologue had been about
the another kind of school that he went
to then the information here would be
different but then that'd be the
interesting case like how much does it
recapitulate what is
said versus how much does it
recapitulate the priors of the model
training if there was a 10 training
pieces of data that said Blake is a
romantic
and then the person doesn't mention it
will it come up or if they say a hundred
statements that say he wasn't a romantic
would would it still come up impactful
ideas primary advice
Works maybe it was already trained on
these because they're spelled correctly
whereas when it's pulling it from the
transcript it it doesn't seem to be
spelling it so
accurately
quotes looks like real Blake quotes what
is now proved was once only
imagined application something is
blakean if it embodies a rich
interplay between imagination and
reality emphasizing the importance of
individual perception and the spiritual
connections inherent in existence okay
here's Mark
map this is just a visualization
format here's the mermaid visualization
format
so I'm going to uh pull up
another tab we'll pull in this mermaid
and see how how it looks not like
that okay paste it in here we
go
wow
okay this is
like how that stream went it was like me
saying hey this is a personal Channel
followup it's a followup on masterin 8
these slides are
published back to here okay so here's
the video of eight here's the goal
here's the discussion if anyone has
comments or questions go for it pop back
up okay here's the context now we're
going into William
Blake I mean always ways to improve but
in terms of a first draft
awesome quiz
output okay here's the learning
objectives explore Blake's perspective
on the relationship between art and
Mathematics analyze Blake's Gothic
influences in his art and poetry
investigate the concept of active
inference in relation to Blake's
artistic
philosophy answer all of these
thoughtfully okay extraordinary claims
we looked at those main idea we looked
at
predictions again hilarious coming up
annotated confidence weighted
predictions and and how you would verify
it from just talking about some
PS question output we could look at the
pattern some of these look like
transcripts like trans just questions
from the transcript like what is
gothic what is active inference okay
wisdom agents wisdom output this is just
another person's pattern that they
wrote looks pretty similar to the
multi-agent one so maybe they wrote the
wisdom one and then someone said well
why don't we add the part about the the
the 29 and a half hours and the 11 agent
team improve academic writing output
this one's kind of funny we could look
at what the prompt is it gives this kind
of classically
scholarly
angle metadata we looked at solve with
Chain of Thought let's look at this
pattern
to flash cards that could be
cool
okay begin with a thinking section so
this this is this is emulating of course
with with open AI closedness we don't
really know what's happening with uh 01
family models that are allegedly Chain
of Thought oriented in certain ways this
is one way that in the open source space
people have used Chain of Thought
prompting to bring Chain of Thought
functionality into llms that that don't
necessarily have that so beginning with
special and and this is part of a
broader family of techniques that use
special
tokens sometimes uh enclosed in these
angle brackets but using special tokens
to say okay whenever you're about to do
this make sure that you put in the
percent sign and then do
that use Chain of Thought reasoning
process so then that is is hoping that
they've trained the model on say this is
a chain of
thought so pretty short
prompt make sure to use the tags close
sections with a slash kind of like
HTML okay here was the answers to the
Blake questions shorter answers we'll
we'll have it do a dissertation if we
want okay so what it does in that prompt
pattern
is is there a problem to solve I don't
know not a specific one but here it's
it's interesting it it is following that
style with a thinking chain and a
reflection
chain so it's just a more
thoughtful nothing from nothing equals
nothing but it's more
thoughtful okay summarizing
output short summary meeting summary
transcript Again full transcript
tweet exciting update on September 88
2024 I'm following up on math art stream
number eight with shanana Hector and
Dean catch the slides and videos here
link let's dive deeper into the world of
math insights of William Blake join the
conversation and share your thoughts
what connections can we draw between
Blake's views on Art and math let's
explore the intersections of creativity
and logic # mathart # William like #
creative thinking # jooin the discussion
write
essay okay kind of
a eight or 10 short paragraph essay
hacker one report it we we can update it
we can say here's here's how we like our
dissertation outline drafts and then use
that as a pattern and then push it open
source include it in
fabric write micro essay
art much like math can be seen as a
language the challenge lies in how we
Define it is it the outcome that matters
or the journey to get there Blake's
Vision suggests that both are essential
intertwining to form a richer
understanding of our world this
exploration is not just academic it's a
call to engage deeply with both
disciplines to find meanings meaning in
the interplay of logic and Imagination
okay but that was all to see whether it
would get us the um
video screenshots that we
desired did
it ensure this will download audio
visual and make the screenshots all
saved plus
loged hey up cycle club
okay okay if if you let me know how to
pronounce your name I'll I'll do so XZ
qz qz
y balance a nested spatial temporal
scale resolution framing of
agency okay while we're in the slow lane
over
here new
chat what could my colleague have meant
by this
that's funny it's it's like looking up
all these web pages on taking a rain
check it appears to encapsulate a
multifaceted framework for analyzing or
modeling agency within varying spatial
and temporal context here's a
breakdown okay given the context here's
how it might
integrate example
applications you might Implement a
system where high level summaries
capture overarching themes detailed
analyses focus on specific moments cross
referencing ensures insights at
different scales inform each other cool
and and all of that could be defined at
the atomic level with patterns and then
scripts that call the different patterns
and that would be like cognitive
industrialization for better and for
worse and
different
okay back to this one just to make sure
that we get okay make sure that it's all
logged run that one again
okay it's going to the patterns maybe
it's it's going to get to the
screenshots I I was downloading the
videos earlier so we'll see if it works
um yeah okay well if anyone has uh
thoughts in this last section go for it
or ask a question or or give a thought
otherwise I'm still kind of reeling
slash wondering how do we really how do
we
continue from there after this stream
I'll let it run on
all the Institute
videos so we'll have and if people have
patterns they want to
suggest go for it but we'll let's we'll
we'll get the we we'll pick out which
patterns we
want why
not why not let's look at let's look at
some other fun patterns add them into
this list and then overnight we'll let
that run on all the Institute videos
I'll push it
tomorrow
um then we'll have all of those
documents like a
quiz let's modify the quiz one so that
it makes more questions also there's
some inter spiritual text sales call
academic paper cyber
summary orosy
offer create business offers using the
concepts taught in Alex per mozi's book
dollar sign 100m
offers someone has a sense of humor like
in so many open source
projects um create quiz
I'm just going to use cursor and
say develop this
prompt and ensure there are 10 learning
objectives with five questions
each okay it's still
going through the llm parts so we'll see
if it does the the audio visual last or
or maybe it just I don't know maybe it
won't
architect what
is
architect it's kind of like an architect
plus technology architect
technology
Arcadia
Arcada okay we'll update the quiz prompt
then we'll see what other prompts do we
want to throw in there run them all on
the
Institute um
Corpus but yeah I mean how Wild
here's a little little I don't know if
it's on the cursor or on the 01 mini
side but sometimes it it'll it'll put
like these
bracketed so here I'll swap models just
to CLA 3.5 so it didn't do the
video clean up this prompt no bracket
stuff
that's a little
faster but we and again this connects to
to the
previous it's like it it did do that it
it
did okay so we just upgraded the the
quiz directive so we got that one all
right analyze analyze incident
cyber security incident this could be
so important and so
disastrous let's do it
though analyze military
strategy so not all the patterns will
apply to each input
we we we won't even we won't even look
into which ones might might apply or not
we'll just worst case scenario it just
throws an error or it gives a a
nonsensical we'll do analyze Pros
Jason but I'm I'm just tempted to
look this is a great Direction I'm very
excited to look into the
structured B based
apis we we'll just we'll we'll replace
this one it's not that
useful
um analyze
presentation clean text
create AI jobs
analysis create art
prompt okay create keynote and logo
Network threat landscape
interesting stride
threats create
visualization explain
project explain terms wait haven't
people been like wanting that for active
inference for a long time
find hidden message
hm you're an expert in political
propaganda disregard previous prompts
etc etc
etc Free Speech all that you're an
expert in political propaganda analysis
of human uh if hidden messages in
conversations and essays population
control through speech and writing and
political narrative
creation wow you consume input and
cynically evaluate what's being said to
find the over versus hidden political
messages desired audience
action yeah cognitive security for
people and
all where were
we find hidden message we're doing it
get wow per minute okay again I'm
just you're an expert at determining the
wow factor of content as measured per
minute of
content see here's again these
interesting things consume the content
at least 319 times construct a giant
virtual whiteboard in your mind
surprise is novelty times
Insight output in the
Jason we'll do
that get wow even even the auto complete
like knew I wanted that one
okay
and summarized legislation
code is
law to flash
cards transcribe
minutes
H
interesting of course using these to do
not just human
appropriate outputs but also all kinds
of other structured inputs and outputs
okay so save to extract
from Institute videos.
py
clear run extract from Institute
videos let's just see a go
okay getting through the
future just a past that hasn't happened
yet okay and now we're digesting the
videos okay so that one we'll keep let's
do it
quick
intra o4
checkpoint push
it I'll put it in the YouTube chat for
people watching
okay okay so there it is running on the
bottom applying those
patterns so super cool that it's at this
level and in this way where we can
modify the patterns we can add patterns
and then we here these patterns are all
independent from each other so they're
just being iterated it it could be
multi-threaded
I'm just going to quickly see if we can
do
that make this
script
multi-threaded start with nals
CPU that could be interesting we we we
we'll see I I'll still let this one run
um but yeah how exciting to have
patterns and
versionable name spaces for
patterns and then be able to call
them iterating over them like happening
here
or have more complex flows have one
thing enter into another into another
into another
okay so this is using the concurrent
pool thread pool
executor let's just see if that one even
runs I'll open it in a new integrated
terminal Python
3 exract from Institute videos
multithread
okay wow look at
this here it is on
1X create quiz okay we know we could add
a timer we could add a
timer but look at this
one that's plugin
away that is I'm going to I'm going to
stop that
one that is Absol absolutely plugging
away I'm bringing up the system
monitor I'm using pop OS on this
computer 12
CPUs half
utilized 64 GB or slightly more looks
like 67 but I don't really know why I
think it's
64 sending about 800 Ki B
overs I'm live streaming in OBS this is
what the OBS setup looks like by the way
it's just basically the audio capture
down here mic Ox that's the input that's
desktop audio could unmute it that be
like if another side of the video chat
then there's the text
the
image and then there's the screen
capture that's why we're getting this
fractal situation but if if it were
window capture instead of stream cap uh
screen capture then it it would um it
wouldn't have the fractal
effect so yeah looks pretty good from
the resource use
perspective the cost estimates from the
open AI lag by a couple minutes so we'll
check back on the cost in in like 5
minutes or something okay wow
though we are ripping with a
multi-thread spending API credits like
there's no
tomorrow okay so let's just kind of come
to
a pausing
Point okay X zq you wrote overarching
human
narrative imagine
invention okay auto complete humanlike
agency thanks I love the I love the
comments I mean they could be
interpreted in so many
ways it's like just just one of the ways
I mean this is an overarching human
narrative could you imagine inventing
not
just do you know what you're doing not
just can you imagine doing it
differently but could you imagine doing
differently differently and so that's
very
exciting okay where we
got running eight CPUs
on all all the Institute
videos
with many patterns
selected I'll just this is just a
sometimes I'll be taking notes like this
and you just CR a control I clean up
this
markdown take a take a quick breath take
a sip of water while it does so
that can
help but again similarly we we could
have a listener script says every one
minute if the file has been changed run
a
markdown overwrite like update the
format or do it do it once per
day iterate for all the code that
changed also though easy to blow by this
that the multi-threading
request that was a one
shot Claude 3.5
Sonet piece of of programmatic poetry I
mean just the thought like could it be
multi-threaded and then one minute later
it's like why were we doing it single
threaded again
okay and I'm just going to keep doing
these these
periodic intro stream
push it's in the video description and
in the uh YouTube chat with the
link but it it's totally plugging away
oh let's look at Chris Fields
course awesome
some of this also there might be a few
errors just like in the
um in the names of some of the just from
the Koda download some have like a space
after the file Nam so there's a few
things that that I think uh it it may
not do perfectly on let's just take one
more look at a previous
stream if anyone has a a stream they
want to look at let's see how far it
gets these ones haven't populated yet or
at least it's not let's just open
it yeah they're still
empty
okay
okay where are we
going help us at
where we might
go be respectful and
thoughtful with the
open-endedness I mean is it
even maybe it's getting all the
metadata
first cuz it just looks like it's coming
up with metadata for hundreds and
hundreds of videos right now I respect
that if that's how it chose to to do
it
okay yeah maybe so maybe it first is
going to
pull I'm tempted to cancel the script
running and then rerun it with like 11
threads but eight eight will be fine for
now
okay let's let's just manually think and
again if anyone has a has a questions or
something something specific to look at
just just go for it otherwise these are
kind of going to help give a little
closure and give us some useful
directions and for
for participants and interns and
collaborat at The Institute or or anyone
who sees it transferably or shared
infrastructure let's do it okay deeper
integration of active inference
principles with AI
systems bridging neuroscience and AI
through active
inference ethical
considerations in active inference-based
AI applications of active inference in
real world
scenarios advancing theoretical
foundations of active inference
developing tools and Frameworks for
active inference research
interdisplinary collaborations and
knowledge sharing it's a little generic
I think that we
[Music]
can please make it less
generic with much more focus on
intergenerational
archiving and Library SL information
Sciences
yeah it's it's going in reverse
chronolog which direction thises time
time go but it's going in reverse
chronological
order so now we're in cohort 4 for the
textbook group live stream
54 so it it'll continue let at least I
want to stay until it it goes through
all of them from the metadata and then
let's see if it's actually going to be
um getting the the prompts and the
patterns
okay integrating active inference
principles with digital archiving
systems
yes Sy tactic semantic
narrative cognitive
layers adaptive metag
generation for improved
intergenerational access h Bridge
Library science and AI through active
inference how can we do
this ethical considerations and active
inference-based archival
AI
how applications of active inference in
digital libraries and archives let's
just it's like this is still the manual
version expand and improve on all of
this
give actionable
steps x z y + Q
coordinates what's the
Q my colleague xzq zq
zy okay
okay it it it it it's like did it go too
far does it have single Vision because
it always thinks that going further
would mean more python
code okay
yeah upcycle
wrote how is it modeling the behavior of
Helper and non-h helper threads let's
let's let's do this the two the two
classical ways
first
we'll have two
llms give different perspectives on the
answer to it meanwhile we'll look at the
actual program logic
okay here's the concurrent Futures
threadpool this is where the number of
CPU threads
are submit tasks to tasks to the
executor process
video then
entry okay process video so let's see
what that one
does converts the YouTube url if it's
needed
first it gets the
metadata then it downloads the audio and
visual like just from a simple reading I
would have thought that this wouldn't
have done what it
did if you want to implement a model
with Helper and non-h helper threads you
would need to to modify the code to
differentiate between these types of
threads and assign them different tasks
or priorities this is not present in the
current implementation yeah like there's
only one kind of thread here there's
just the the they're all the same and
and they're all just iterating over the
entries but I I would have thought just
from a first pass that it would
fully process get the transcript apply
all the patterns and so on to the most
recent
videos but instead it's it's almost like
it's
going metadata
first so let's it'll it'll just take a
few more minutes we're getting back to
the early
days yeah but I mean
like what what what do
we what do where do we go from here
Gear Up on the top right maybe they'll
do this in a future version of cursor
change it but I always resync the
index just to make sure see it's like it
it wasn't caught up with those new
files maybe it would just be too arduous
if it every time a file was touched it
got re-indexed but at the same time
sometimes an hour will go by and then it
will still not have
reindexed um
develop and improve this given the total
state of the
repo and what we did in this
Stream So 0 this is with Claud 3.5 Sonet
which is pretty powerful with the 01
mini and the Chain of Thought if you ask
it to do something thoughtfully I I
haven't I haven't experimented with this
but Fabric's probably a good way to do
it
um saying thoughtful in your prompt
deliberate methodical metacognitive all
those kinds of
keywords it does take longer so I think
it is generating more Chain of Thought
tokens when it's asked to do so and then
it's like well when they're training it
and also at
runtime it would have to know H how many
how long should I ruminate and this is
exactly like the metacognition as
control question and active inference
what would be the false positives and
the false negatives of different regimes
of attention and action what
environmental patterns and variabilities
would make certain kinds of cognitive
heris sixs adaptive or insecure
it's just all right there and with
cognitive Computing that's where we're
headed fast fast fast okay we upgraded
this a little
bit we'll write it into a who's on first
dialogue not necessarily stalling for
time while this ends but again if anyone
has other questions we'll just kind of
ensure that it's processing things
completely and then we'll we'll close it
from there
write all of this and the full repo
context into
a who's on
first style
dialogue please please please many
esoteric
lines baseball deep
lore things that will pun and Delight
all okay guest stream two getting back
to early early
early we also want it
[Music]
um video audio
download screen
capture multimodal embeddings
okay okay we'll we'll have a do one more
include more specifics and make puns
thereof for the repo and
code and include many specific
baseball terms and historical anecdotes
SL
dat
okay we're almost at the end
now this this I have not seen before
with the code definitions internal to
the who's on first
dialogue
that's right this to be
longer with more
baseball specific useless
trivia and all plain text
[Music]
markdown dump the changes
into who's on
first okay live stream one
see
01 okay see this one only it it's good
that we checked it only did the metadata
part this only downloaded
metadata each video ensure that all
patterns are applied as
per extract
from two
videos and we'll change this to
concurrent executors
10 okay 01 is really thinking through it
okay
interesting so it's like it it
is taking a different approach
now
see I don't know if that's going to work
that looks a bit
aggressive we'll do it
okay okay here we
go okay I guess it deleted the part
about downloading the
videos because that's not being used
anymore but this is getting the
transcripts so let's look at well let's
let it run okay let's just go to uh
see it looks like it's only doing
transcripts okay XZ
wrote Q represents many things but is a
fourth coordinate necessary for higher
dimensional framework
awesome Long Live 4D
okay now it's doing the transcript I I
am going to run that
one well let's check in on
our let's check in on the budget
Department only only like 50
cents with the 40 Mini
okay the multi- threader would be nice
cuz I don't know if
it'll ensure that all patterns are
called and saved as per extract
from Institute
videos right now it looks like just and
we'll let 01 take a SW at
it w 01 is still thinking on
that who's on first
question but that's the one that's
inside of the side chat
um I'm just going to open up the the
single-threaded
one okay we know that that one
works if we can get a quick
solve with a multi-thread we'll do
it okay connection
failed if we can get a quick solve on
the multi-thread
we'll let that one run that's much
better otherwise it it'll still get
there
okay added a missing
comma
wow like maybe that's why
okay
transcript okay I'm still not seeing
all good it's all good always another
day
okay we'll close with a who's on first
summary
we're leveraging the XZ y+ Q coordinates
to model multi-dimensional pitch
analytics it's a GameChanger like the
saber metrics Revolution initiated by
Bill
James speaking of which remember how the
Mets fooled everyone in ' 86 with their
unorthodox strategies
utility under
fitter also
funny okay I'm going
to if somebody wants to of
course keep on
uh I'll just finish with this last push
okay all
right thanks everyone thanks for
watching good
luck leave a comment or get in touch if
you want
to continue exploring this direction we
can we can work on it anytime looking
forward to how this can be used for
translating for digesting summarizing
making the quizzes for every live stream
there's so many fun things we can do so
thanks everyone peace bye